[
    {
        "description": "a wise mage.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I can help.", 
        "keyword_1": "HELP", 
        "keyword_2": "RIDD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The riddle!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "If the eight\nphilosophies of\navatarhood\ncombine into and\nare made from\ntruth, love\n& courage...", 
        "name": "Joshua", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "More?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "What one thing\ncreates and is\ncreated by all\ntruths, all love\n& all courage?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a fair maiden.", 
        "health": "Fine thanks.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I can help thee.", 
        "keyword_1": "HELP", 
        "keyword_2": "ONE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Seek ye to know\nhow the eight\nvirtues form\ninto the three\nprinciples.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Seek ye to know\nwhat one thing\nthe three\nprinciples of\nvirtue combine\ninto!", 
        "name": "Juliet", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Know ye this?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Seek it!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Now the one!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a dancing\njester.", 
        "health": "Perfectly hoppy!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "To entertain.", 
        "keyword_1": "JEST", 
        "keyword_2": "BARD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A jester needs\na good bard!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Our bard is\nvery good.", 
        "name": "Jester Twin", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou like\nthe music?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A shame, we do!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then you should\ngo to Britain\nfor there lives\nthe best!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a burly guard.", 
        "health": "Great!", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I guard the\ncastle and my\nliege!", 
        "keyword_1": "GUAR", 
        "keyword_2": "LIEGE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A guard must\nbe a valiant\nwarrior!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I serve\nLord British!", 
        "name": "a guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou the\nmost valiant\nwarrior?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Still flee not\nfrom battle!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then thou should\nbe a guard!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a person with\na white hat.", 
        "health": "Well... all but\nmy finger,\nwhich I cut!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am the chef.", 
        "keyword_1": "FOOD", 
        "keyword_2": "COOK", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Food, glorious\nfood, to cook is\nmy life!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Cooking is a\npracticed art.", 
        "name": "Le Chef", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Do you eat?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then thou\nmust be a\nspiritualist!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then thou should\ntry my soup!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a reaper.", 
        "health": "Not so good,\nno one to eat\nin here!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I kill\nadventurers!", 
        "keyword_1": "KILL", 
        "keyword_2": "THIN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "There is a thing\nwhich can kill\nmany!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Knowledge of it\nis found at\nBuccaneer's Den!", 
        "name": "a reaper", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Will you seek\nthis thing?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then thou must\nbe stupid.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It brings\ngreat power!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 32
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a ragged soul.", 
        "health": "Very poor.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I have none.", 
        "keyword_1": "CRIM", 
        "keyword_2": "PRIS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Crime is an\nevil thing!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Here I pay for\nmy crimes!", 
        "name": "a nameless\nprisoner", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Are you a\npirate?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I hope that\nthis is true!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "You may never\ncomplete thy\nquests, for evil\nmakes not an\navatar!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise mage.", 
        "health": "I am old,\nvery old...", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am here\nto help thee.", 
        "keyword_1": "HELP", 
        "keyword_2": "CAST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Seek help in\nthe castles!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Seek:\nthe Lycaeum,\nEmpath Abbey,\nSerpent's\nCastle!", 
        "name": "Zorin", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou\ngo hither?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Find therein all\nnamed Antos and\nask of the bell,\nbook, and\ncandle!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a burly guard.", 
        "health": "Couldn't be\nbetter!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I guard the\ncastle and all\nwithin.", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "CAST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I guard the\ncastle!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The castle is\nfair and strong!", 
        "name": "a guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Do you seek\nLord British?", 
        "question_no_answer": "He will aid\nyou if you\nare in need!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "He is on the\nupper level in\nthe throne room.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "water.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I hold a secret.", 
        "keyword_1": "SECR", 
        "keyword_2": "ALTAR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "To what?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "There are three\naltar rooms\nwhich connect\nthe bottom\nlevels of all\neight dungeons!", 
        "name": "Water", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "More?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "If the correct\ncolors of stones\nare used in the\naltars, a key of\nthree parts can\nbe gained!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a shepherdess\nboth strong\nand beautiful.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I watch\nthe water.", 
        "keyword_1": "WATER", 
        "keyword_2": "PEACE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It brings\nme peace.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I come from\na proud city.", 
        "name": "Shawn", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou proud?", 
        "question_no_answer": "My towne was\ndestroyed for\nits pride. The\nruins lie on an\nisle at lat-K'J\"\nlong-L'L\"!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Hmmm.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an injured\nfighter.", 
        "health": "I have a\ngrievous wound.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I fight for\nmy country.", 
        "keyword_1": "WOUND", 
        "keyword_2": "COUN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Deep.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Britannia.", 
        "name": "Seesha", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Fight ye for\nBritannia?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Hmm.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then seek out\nthe smith named\nZircon in Minoc\nfor he made the\nmystic arms,\nonly they will\nsave thee in the\nabyss!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a bouncing\njester.", 
        "health": "Good, thanks.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am the royal\njester", 
        "keyword_1": "JEST", 
        "keyword_2": "CLUE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Welcome unto\nthe castle\nBritannia!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Speak ye unto\nthe waters of\nthe well and ask\nof altars!", 
        "name": "Chuckles", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou\nan ankh?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then why art\nthou here?", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then enter\nin peace!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a guard.", 
        "health": "Excellent", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "A guard", 
        "keyword_1": "GUAR", 
        "keyword_2": "TREA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "We guard the\ncastle and its\ntreasures.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "That is not\nyour business.", 
        "name": "a guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Do you mean\nto steal?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then please\nleave at once!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I believe you\nwill find that\nan unfruitful\nventure.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a solemn ranger.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I search for\nthe inner light.", 
        "keyword_1": "LIGHT", 
        "keyword_2": "SHRI", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Seek inner light\nin the shrines!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Runes are needed\nto enter\nshrines!", 
        "name": "Sheila", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou know\nof mantra?", 
        "question_no_answer": "The mantra are\nchants needed\nto focus thy\nthoughts while\nmeditating.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a grim shepherd.", 
        "health": "I am fine, but\nthou must\ngo back!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am here\nto warn thee!", 
        "keyword_1": "WARN", 
        "keyword_2": "PERIL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Ahead lies a\nperilous place!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Once thou enters\nthou may not\nreturn whence\nthee came!", 
        "name": "Landri", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou go on?", 
        "question_no_answer": "That is good.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then thou art\ndoomed!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a stately baron.", 
        "health": "Very well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I rule this\nprovince.", 
        "keyword_1": "PROV", 
        "keyword_2": "WORD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "My Lady Beth can\ntell thee more!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I know but\none of three\nsyllables.", 
        "name": "Robert Frasier", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou wish\nto know it now?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Perhaps\nanother time.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It is 'VER'!\nSeek ye now the\nother parts!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a charming lady.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I rule with\nmy Lord.", 
        "keyword_1": "RULE", 
        "keyword_2": "PROV", 
        "keyword_response_1": "This province.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Our people\nbelieve in truth\nas a way of life\nand live it to\nthe fullest!", 
        "name": "Beth Frasier", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou\nseek truth?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then thou shalt\nnot find it!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then may thou\nfind it!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a sleepy guard.", 
        "health": "Very sleepy.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Guard the gate,\nguard the baron,\nguard the\nbaroness, watch\nthe towers....", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "HOURS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have been here\nfor hours!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yes, many hours!", 
        "name": "a guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "See why\nI'm tired?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Bum!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It's hard work\nand long hours\nin the baronial\nguard!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 14
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise old sage.", 
        "health": "My bones ache\nbut my mind\nis sharp!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am an old\nwizard, but have\nmuch to show!", 
        "keyword_1": "SHOW", 
        "keyword_2": "TELE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Here in my\ntelescope!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Search there by\nthe end, thou\nshalt find\na knob.", 
        "name": "Palamar", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou\nsee where?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Look!!!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Set the dial and\nthou shalt see!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an old druid,\nwho looks\nstrangely\nfamiliar.", 
        "health": "Old and frail,\nI've seen many\nquests!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I hold great\nknowledge.", 
        "keyword_1": "KNOW", 
        "keyword_2": "BOOK", 
        "keyword_response_1": "What is it\nyou seek?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Seek ye the book\nof truth where\nother books lie.", 
        "name": "Father Antos", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou on\nthe quest?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "May thou\nsucceed!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a brawny guard.", 
        "health": "Bit tired.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I guard the\nthrone room.", 
        "keyword_1": "THRONE", 
        "keyword_2": "TRUTH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Throne of truth!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "There are four\ntownes that\nfollow the\nprinciple of\ntruth.", 
        "name": "Jon", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Know which?", 
        "question_no_answer": "There are\neight possible\ncombinations of\nthe three\nprinciples,\nthere are eight\ncities!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall mage\nwearing strange\narmour.", 
        "health": "Well!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I advise.", 
        "keyword_1": "ADVI", 
        "keyword_2": "ARMOUR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Thou would be\nwell advised to\nvisit the Seer\noften!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I wear\nmystic armour.", 
        "name": "Scatu", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou a\npartial avatar?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "When thou art 8\nparts avatar,\nseek Zircon in\nMinoc and ask of\nmystics!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a short druid.", 
        "health": "Why I am fine,\nyou too I hope.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "Research", 
        "keyword_1": "RESE", 
        "keyword_2": "JUST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I am looking for\nthe book of\njustice!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It must be here\nsomewhere!", 
        "name": "Estro", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou never\ncommitted *any*\ncrime!?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then speak to\nthe judge in\nYew!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I believe thou\nart boasting\na lie!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a stately\nwizard.", 
        "health": "Very well,\nthanks!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "To welcome thee!", 
        "keyword_1": "WELC", 
        "keyword_2": "FOUR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Yes, welcome to\nthe Lycaeum, the\nkeep of truth!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The dungeon\naltar rooms need\n4 stones each!", 
        "name": "Tymus", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Know ye how many\ncities follow\nthe principles\nof truth?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Travel and\nlearn!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "How many?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a person lost\nin thought.", 
        "health": "I am in a\nmeditative\nstate.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek to\nknow truth.", 
        "keyword_1": "TRUTH", 
        "keyword_2": "MEDI", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The principle\nupon which I\nmeditate.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Meditate at each\nshrine for 1, 2\nand 3 cycles,\nthen shalt thou\nknow the paths\nof goodness!", 
        "name": "a truth\nseeker", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an injured\nwarrior.", 
        "health": "My wounds are\ngrievous!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "None now!", 
        "keyword_1": "WARR", 
        "keyword_2": "WOUNDS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "No more!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I lost in a\ndungeon altar\nroom!", 
        "name": "a fighter", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou\nseen one?", 
        "question_no_answer": "They connect the\ndungeons unto\neach other!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Notice that\neach of the\nthree rooms\nconnect to four\ndungeons each!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall agile\nman.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am the\nlibrarian.", 
        "keyword_1": "LIBR", 
        "keyword_2": "TRUTH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Herein is the\nlargest store\nof knowledge in\nBritannia except\nthe codex!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Look under 'T'.", 
        "name": "Lord Terence", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou looking\nfor a particular\nbook?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Feel free\nto browse.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Which book?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a flighty\njester.", 
        "health": "Unhappy.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "To entertain!", 
        "keyword_1": "ENTER", 
        "keyword_2": "UNHAPP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Ah, not now.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Because my\nfriend Chuckles\nwon't tell me\nhis secret!", 
        "name": "Zajac", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou know\nChuckles?", 
        "question_no_answer": "He lives in\nthe castle\nBritannia ask\nhim of his clue!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Why dost thou\nnot ask him for\nhis clue!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a strong guard.", 
        "health": "Very good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "To watch the\ntreasures.", 
        "keyword_1": "TREAS", 
        "keyword_2": "VALUE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The treasures\nare of great\nvalue!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yes, much gold.", 
        "name": "Catriona", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou intend\nto steal?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Good, you had\nme worried!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I shan't stop\nthee.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a noble wizard.", 
        "health": "Good enough.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I teach magical\nspells.", 
        "keyword_1": "SPELLS", 
        "keyword_2": "RECALL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have a\nspecialty!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yes,\nresurrection\nit takes: ash,\nginseng, garlic,\nsilk, bloodmoss,\nand mandrake!", 
        "name": "Nigel, at thy\nservice", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou know\nwhat it is?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Sorry.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "What do I call\nthe spell?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a pitiful\nbeggar.", 
        "health": "I am cold\nand sick!\noh... please...", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I sit and beg\noh... please...", 
        "keyword_1": "BEG", 
        "keyword_2": "SICK", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Yes, please\ngive me money!\noh... please...", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I have the\nblack plague!", 
        "name": "Shylock the Meek", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou\nhelp me?\nOh... please...", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh... please...", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Oh... please...", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a stately baron.", 
        "health": "Very well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I rule this\nprovince.", 
        "keyword_1": "PROV", 
        "keyword_2": "WORD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "My Lady Marcy\ncan tell thee\nmore!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I know but\none of three\nsyllables.", 
        "name": "Lord Robert", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou wish\nto know it now?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Perhaps\nanother time.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It is 'AMO'!\nSeek ye now the\nother parts!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a charming lady.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I rule with\nmy Lord.", 
        "keyword_1": "RULE", 
        "keyword_2": "PROV", 
        "keyword_response_1": "This province.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Our people\nbelieve in love\nas a way of life\nand live it to\nthe fullest!", 
        "name": "Lady Marcy", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou\nseek love?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then thou shalt\nnot find it!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then may thou\nfind it!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a lovely lady.", 
        "health": "Overworked!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a lady\nin waiting.", 
        "keyword_1": "LADY", 
        "keyword_2": "HORN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I serve Marcy.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "There is a\npaladin by the\nname of Malchor.\nHe can lead thee\nto the silver\nhorn!", 
        "name": "Suzanna", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou allowed\nto be in here?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou should\nleave!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I doubt it!\nThou should\nleave!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 40
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an ankh.", 
        "health": "I exist.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I resonate\nthoughts.", 
        "keyword_1": "RESON", 
        "keyword_2": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "What are thy\nthoughts?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Seek ye the\ncandle of love\nfor only with it\nand two other\nparts might thou\nenter the abyss!", 
        "name": "Life", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Dost thou\nhave it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ask the bard\nbeyond the\nsecret passage!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a guard.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I guard the\npassages.", 
        "keyword_1": "PASS", 
        "keyword_2": "DANG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "There is\nno danger.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Well not\ncompared to a\ndungeon altar\nroom!", 
        "name": "the pass guard", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Hast thou solved\nthe altars?", 
        "question_no_answer": "From them a\nthree part key\nis gained,\nneeded to enter\nthe chamber of\nthe codex!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a guard.", 
        "health": "Top notch.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "A gate guard", 
        "keyword_1": "GATE", 
        "keyword_2": "ABBEY", 
        "keyword_response_1": "To the abbey.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Here, in the oak\ngrove many find\nthe meaning of\npeace and love!", 
        "name": "a gate guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou\nsaturated with\nlove?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Visit the small\nshrine within\nthe abbey!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then thou need\nnot be here!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a young bard\nplaying a lute.", 
        "health": "Pretty good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a bard,\nI sing songs.", 
        "keyword_1": "SONGS", 
        "keyword_2": "CAND", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Oh, all types.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The candle of\nlove is found in\na secret place\nhidden off\nLock Lake!", 
        "name": "Derek the Bard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou like\nthis one?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas,\nit was new.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thanks, I just\nwrote it!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small but\nstately child.", 
        "health": "Very well,\nthank you!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I welcome thee\nunto the Abbey!", 
        "keyword_1": "GROVE", 
        "keyword_2": "OAK", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A grove of oak.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "There four\nprofession types\nseek truth!", 
        "name": "Chinup", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou here in\nsearch of love?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Perhaps then the\noak grove.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Perhaps then the\noak grove!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall woman.", 
        "health": "Good.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I counsel those\nwho enter\nthe grove.", 
        "keyword_1": "COUN", 
        "keyword_2": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Herein thou may\nfind insights\ninto love,\nwithin thyself\nor the others\nhere in the\ngrove.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Ask the others.", 
        "name": "Diane", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou the\nmost loving\nperson?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Strive for love!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Doubtful!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a solemn bard.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I relate love\nand compassion.", 
        "keyword_1": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_2": "COMP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "When the three\ncombine in eight\nways love alone\nis compassion.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Of the\neight avatar\nattributes\ncompassion is\nderived from\nlove alone.", 
        "name": "Benjamin", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou well?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad...", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Very good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a druid,\nlost in thought.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I ponder love\nand justice.", 
        "keyword_1": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_2": "JUST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "When three build\neight, truth\ntempered by love\nbecomes justice!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Justice is one\nof the eight\navatar virtues\nand derives from\ntruth and love.", 
        "name": "Deirdre", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I see.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Most good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a hearty tinker.", 
        "health": "Fine", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am thinking of\nlove's part in\nsacrifice.", 
        "keyword_1": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_2": "SACR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Love of others\nand the courage\nto face even\ndeath is\nself-sacrifice.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Sacrifice is\nbuilt upon the\nmotive of love\nand the ability\nof courage.", 
        "name": "Thomas", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Thyself?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Shame.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a solemn\nranger.", 
        "health": "Most well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I follow the\nspiritual path.", 
        "keyword_1": "SPIR", 
        "keyword_2": "BEING", 
        "keyword_response_1": "My spirituality\nis not a\nreligion, but a\nsearching to\nknow and improve\nmy own inner\nbeing.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "My being is\nbased on my own\ntruth, love and\ncourage.", 
        "name": "Lastro", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "And thee?", 
        "question_no_answer": "So sad.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mumbling\nbeggar.", 
        "health": "Not so good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek salvation", 
        "keyword_1": "MUMB", 
        "keyword_2": "SALV", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The...ankh...\nspoke to me!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I am but a poor\ndestitute beggar\nI have nothing!", 
        "name": "Humlock", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Will you give me\nsome money?", 
        "question_no_answer": "But I am in\nmost dire need!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I would be soooo\ngrateful....", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a bold paladin.", 
        "health": "Just now\nfully healed!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I solve quests", 
        "keyword_1": "QUESTS", 
        "keyword_2": "HORN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "My last quest\ntook me near\nSpiritwood.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Some say that\nthe silver horn\nis buried on a\nsmall isle off\nthe tip of\nSpiritwood.", 
        "name": "Malchor", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou\non a quest?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Best of luck\nto thee!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise druid.", 
        "health": "I am getting old\nand frail.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I hold great\nwisdom.", 
        "keyword_1": "WISDOM", 
        "keyword_2": "CANDLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "What dost thou\nask of me?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Thou dost need\nthe candle of\nlove to enter\nthe abyss.", 
        "name": "Brother Antos", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou\nknow where\nto find it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Meditate on love\nat our shrine.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Very good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a stately baron.", 
        "health": "Very well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I rule this\nprovince.", 
        "keyword_1": "PROV", 
        "keyword_2": "WORD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Yes, these\nislands and\nmuch more.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I know but\none of three\nsyllables-'COR'.", 
        "name": "Sentri", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou know\nthe four cities\nof courage?", 
        "question_no_answer": "They are Jhelom,\nMinoc, Trinsic\nand Skara Brae.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Very good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a very\nbig guard.", 
        "health": "Very strong!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Guard the gates,\nof course.", 
        "keyword_1": "GATES", 
        "keyword_2": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "These are the\ngates to Serpent\nCastle.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Guard, watch,\nprotect.", 
        "name": "the gate guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou here to\nfind courage?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then perhaps to\nbecome a guard!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then thou art at\nthe right place.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wounded\nsailor.", 
        "health": "I alone survived\nthe shipwreck.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a sailor.", 
        "keyword_1": "SHIP", 
        "keyword_2": "WHEEL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The H.M.S. Cape.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "She went down in\nthe deep waters\nof the bay in\nthe Cape of\nHeroes!", 
        "name": "Lassorn", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Ever heard\nof her?", 
        "question_no_answer": "She was a\nmighty vessel!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "She was a\nmighty vessel!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a seasoned\nfighter.", 
        "health": "Just healed.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I fight for\nBritannia!", 
        "keyword_1": "ABYSS", 
        "keyword_2": "CODEX", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The Great\nStygian Abyss\nholds The Codex\nof Ultimate\nWisdom!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I know little.", 
        "name": "Roark", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou well?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou hast come\nto the right\nplace.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then strive to\nfind the secrets\nof the abyss.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a ranger\nengrossed in\ntraining.", 
        "health": "Excellent.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am training!", 
        "keyword_1": "TRAIN", 
        "keyword_2": "DUNG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I train so that\nI might survive\nthe dungeons!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I plan to\nconquer the\nsecret of the\naltar rooms.", 
        "name": "a ranger", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Wimp.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ask our teacher\nabout the rooms\nfor she knows\nmuch!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "the training\nmaster.", 
        "health": "Prime.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I train warriors\nto fight with\ncourage!", 
        "keyword_1": "TRAIN", 
        "keyword_2": "ROOM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Train well and\nthy courage can\ngrow with\nconfidence.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "In the altar\nroom of courage\nuse the red,\norange, purple\nand white\nstones!", 
        "name": "Shyra", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Wilt thou train?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Pity.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Bravo!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a stern guard.", 
        "health": "Most good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I guard our lord", 
        "keyword_1": "LORD", 
        "keyword_2": "CAST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Sentri rules\nthis castle.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "This castle is\nbuilt on\ncourage.", 
        "name": "a baronial guard", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou wish\nan audience\nwith Sentri?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then do not\ndisturb him.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Granted, enter.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a burly guard.", 
        "health": "Excellent.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "We guard our\nlord's treasure.", 
        "keyword_1": "TREAS", 
        "keyword_2": "DUNG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "This treasure is\nnot for thee", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Seek out Durham\nfor knowledge of\ndungeons.", 
        "name": "a treasure guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou intend\nto steal\nour lord's\ntreasure?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Wise move!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Fool!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a bold fighter.", 
        "health": "Quite well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I fight with\ncourage!", 
        "keyword_1": "COUR", 
        "keyword_2": "BELL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Courage makes\nkings out of\nknaves!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The bell of\ncourage lies at\nthe bottom of a\ndeep well at sea\nfound at\nlat-N'A\"\nlong-L'A\"", 
        "name": "Garam", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then train!", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall fighter.", 
        "health": "Fairly well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I quest\nfor glory!", 
        "keyword_1": "QUEST", 
        "keyword_2": "DUNG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I feel that when\non a quest my\nlife has\npurpose!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The altar room\nof courage gives\nthe third part\nof a key.", 
        "name": "Durham", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou on\na quest?", 
        "question_no_answer": "What a loss.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then thy life\nhas meaning!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a buxom guard.", 
        "health": "So far, so good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I guard this\npassage.", 
        "keyword_1": "GARAM", 
        "keyword_2": "DURHAM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "He is in the\nwest chamber.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "He is in the\neast chamber.", 
        "name": "Lori", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou looking\nfor someone?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then be on\nthy way!", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Who?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a handsome\nguard.", 
        "health": "So far, so good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I guard this\npassage.", 
        "keyword_1": "GARAM", 
        "keyword_2": "DURHAM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "He is in the\nwest chamber.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "He is in the\neast chamber.", 
        "name": "Samuel", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou looking\nfor someone?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then be on\nthy way!", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Who?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a destitute,\nstinking beggar.", 
        "health": "I've lost\na hand!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I cannot work.", 
        "keyword_1": "HAND", 
        "keyword_2": "ORBS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It was eaten\nby a zorn.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "An orb of blue\nlight will raise\nthy strength,\ndexterity or\nintelligence,\nbut at a cost!", 
        "name": "Roderick", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou give\nme gold?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Stingy!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou art kind.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise druid.", 
        "health": "Well enough.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I have important\ninformation.", 
        "keyword_1": "INFORM", 
        "keyword_2": "BELL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "On what subject?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The bell of\ncourage is\nneeded to enter\nthe abyss.", 
        "name": "Sister Antos", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou\nhave it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then ask the\nfighter Garam\nfor he knows\nwhere it lies!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Very good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a spiny nixie!", 
        "health": "Nice and wet!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I swim the seas!", 
        "keyword_1": "SEAS", 
        "keyword_2": "SHIPS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "There are many\nships at the\nbottom!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A survivor would\nknow where to\nsearch.", 
        "name": "Noxum", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou\nheard of the\nH.M.S. Cape?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A great ship!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "She had a\nmagical wheel\nthat would\nstrengthen her\nhull!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a beautiful\npaladin!", 
        "health": "Very well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I welcome thee\nunto Serpent\nCastle!", 
        "keyword_1": "SENTRI", 
        "keyword_2": "VISIT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "He is the lord\nhere, take the\nwest passage.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Take the east\npassage.", 
        "name": "Michelle", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou well?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then thou should\nvisit our\nhealer!", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Very good,\nperhaps thou\nseeks Sentri.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a young mage.", 
        "health": "Quite good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek\nadventure!", 
        "keyword_1": "ADVENT", 
        "keyword_2": "QUEST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Yes, I hope to\ngo on a great\nquest!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The quest of the\navatar is noble\nindeed!", 
        "name": "Mariah", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou on\na quest?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Wish thou were!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I wish I could\njoin thee!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a starving\njournalist.", 
        "health": "I feel fine...\nif I could just\nquit smoking!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a writer.", 
        "keyword_1": "WRIT", 
        "keyword_2": "SMOK", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It's low paid,\nbut glamorous!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Cough...cough...", 
        "name": "Tracie", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Do you smoke?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Don't start!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I can tell\nby the smell!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a regal paladin.", 
        "health": "Well indeed.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I speak of the\nvirtues of\nhonesty!", 
        "keyword_1": "HONEST", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A few honest men\nare better than\nnumbers!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The mantra of\nthe shrine\nof honesty\nis 'AHM'.", 
        "name": "Cromwell", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou strive\nto be honest?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Shame!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then you will\nneed the mantra.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mystic wizard.", 
        "health": "I've been better", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I live an\nhonest life.", 
        "keyword_1": "HONEST", 
        "keyword_2": "EVIL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Speak the truth\nand shame the\nevil forces!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Evil still\nexists in\nour hearts\nand souls!", 
        "name": "Rebelias", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek\nto conquer thine\nown evil?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Wretch!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "The quest of\na lifetime!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a playful child.", 
        "health": "Feeling good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am your\nfriend.", 
        "keyword_1": "FRIEND", 
        "keyword_2": "HONEST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Honest friends\nare few!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "My friend\nWilliam knows\nwhere the rune\nof honesty is.", 
        "name": "Christen", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou my\nfriend?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I am sad.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "That makes\nme happy.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a meek shepherd.", 
        "health": "Pretty good.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I am shepherd.", 
        "keyword_1": "HUMBLE", 
        "keyword_2": "HUMI", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Humility is\nnot derived from\nthe direct\ncombination of\ntruth, love or\ncourage.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Humility is to\nact and be\nhumble.", 
        "name": "Patric the\nHumble Shepherd", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou\ntotally humble?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Strive to be.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Doubtful!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a dying young\nwizard.", 
        "health": "I will soon die.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am apprentice\nto the great\nwizard Nigel!", 
        "keyword_1": "NIGEL", 
        "keyword_2": "DIE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I will soon\nneed to use\nthe spell he\ncalls 'recall'.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Pass on.", 
        "name": "Shazom", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou\nmet Nigel?", 
        "question_no_answer": "He lives at\nthe Lycaeum.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Seek him out for\nhe will teach\nthee.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise wizard.", 
        "health": "Getting on.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I create tales\nof honesty.", 
        "keyword_1": "HONES", 
        "keyword_2": "CORRUP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Remember, there\nis no terror\nin threats for\nI am strong\nin honesty!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Corruption wins\nnot more than\nhonesty!", 
        "name": "Shakespeare", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou strive\nto be honest?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Fool!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Beware\ncorruption!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall mage.", 
        "health": "Been better.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I strive to live\nan honest life!", 
        "keyword_1": "HONE", 
        "keyword_2": "TRUTH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "An honest soul\nneed remember\nno lies!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Truth is the\nroot of honesty!", 
        "name": "Browning", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou\nnever lied?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Truth never\nhurts the\nteller!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "That seems\nunlikely!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an elderly\nwoman.", 
        "health": "Tired, so tired.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am an\nalchemist.", 
        "keyword_1": "ALCHEM", 
        "keyword_2": "REAGEN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I know how best\nto mix reagents!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A sleep spell\nactually\nrequires but\none part\nspider silk!", 
        "name": "Cosima", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou know\nhow to best mix\nspells?", 
        "question_no_answer": "The secret's in\nthe reagents!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a hunched,\ninsane looking\nman!", 
        "health": "Health?", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I move the sun!", 
        "keyword_1": "SUN", 
        "keyword_2": "MOON", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The moons are\nmy enemies!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "When I die the\nworld will end!", 
        "name": "Daranor", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Do you believe\nmy story!?!?...", 
        "question_no_answer": "Idiot, you must\nthink I am\ninsane!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then we must\nfell the moons!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an old gypsy.", 
        "health": "I predict I will\nbe fine today!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a fortune\nteller, I read\npalms.", 
        "keyword_1": "PALM", 
        "keyword_2": "FORTUN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Palms tell\nfortunes!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Give thy palm.", 
        "name": "Inoo", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou wish\nthy destiny?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Wise choice.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "A great quest\nwill lead thee\ninto the abyss\nwhere the codex\nawaits!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall mage.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I bear greetings\nfrom the fair\ncity of\nMoonglow.", 
        "keyword_1": "INN", 
        "keyword_2": "HEALER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "We have an\nexcellent inn.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Our healer is\none of the best!", 
        "name": "Calabrini", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek\nan inn or\nhealing?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Perhaps, the\nshrine which\nlies on an isle\nto the north!", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Which?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a bouncy jester.", 
        "health": "Very good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I earn an honest\nliving, jesting!", 
        "keyword_1": "HONEST", 
        "keyword_2": "JEST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Honest labor\nbears a lovely\nface!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I love a\ngood jest.", 
        "name": "Dekker", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou art\nprobably a\nsourpuss!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "We ought to\nexchange jokes\nsometime!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a child eating\na sandwich.", 
        "health": "Pretty good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Oh, not much.", 
        "keyword_1": "SANDW", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It's a peanut\nbutter and grape\njelly on lightly\ntoasted bread!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Search for the\nrune of honesty\nby Mariah's\ngold!", 
        "name": "William", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wouldst thou\nlike a bite?", 
        "question_no_answer": "It's awful\nyummy!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Yummy, huh!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a battered mage.", 
        "health": "Fading.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I used to search\nfor the blue\nstone.", 
        "keyword_1": "STONE", 
        "keyword_2": "USE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The stone of\nhonesty is found\non an altar in\nthe dungeon of\nDeceit.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It is used\nwithin the\ndungeon altar\nrooms and in\nthe abyss.", 
        "name": "Tyrone", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou\nsearch?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Hmm.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Know its uses!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a charming bard.", 
        "health": "Good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I play for\nthe people.", 
        "keyword_1": "PLAY", 
        "keyword_2": "COMP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I play my lute\nand receive the\ngood wishes of\nthe people.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "If you treat\nsomeone else\nwell then they\nwill have reason\nto do the same.", 
        "name": "Iolo", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Do you like\nmy music?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A shame.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I would\njoin thee!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a charming\njester.", 
        "health": "Very well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I dance and\nsing for the\nchildren.", 
        "keyword_1": "DANCE", 
        "keyword_2": "BEGG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Dance is good\nfor the soul.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "To give to a\nbeggar shows\ncompassion.", 
        "name": "Gweno", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Do you give\nto the needy?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Beggars are\nthankful for\nsmall donations.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small child.", 
        "health": "Very happy.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Singing", 
        "keyword_1": "SING", 
        "keyword_2": "HO EYO", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The song goes:\nHo eyo he hum!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It means:\nlove to one\nand all!", 
        "name": "a child", 
        "pronoun": "The child", 
        "question": "Do you like\nthe song?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then help us\nspread the word!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a guard.", 
        "health": "Good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I guard the\nbridge.", 
        "keyword_1": "BRIDGE", 
        "keyword_2": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Across the\nbridge our\npeople dance\nand sing!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yep.", 
        "name": "a guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Would thou like\nto join them?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then you have\nno business\nacross the\nbridge.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Remember, an\nopen heart is\nthe first step\non the path to\nwisdom!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a spicy woman.", 
        "health": "Healthy.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a\nfighting bard.", 
        "keyword_1": "BARD", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Bards know\nmany things.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The rune of\ncompassion lies\nat the end of a\nhall somewhere\nin this towne.", 
        "name": "Pepper", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek\nsomething?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas, I may have\nbeen able to\nhelp.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "What might\nthat be?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a seasoned\nfighter.", 
        "health": "Fairly well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I search for\nthe mystery of\nthe magic orbs.", 
        "keyword_1": "ORBS", 
        "keyword_2": "MAGIC", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A one-handed\nbeggar knows\ntheir secrets!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Magic orbs.", 
        "name": "Thevel", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou\nseen him?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Find him in\nSerpent castle\nfor he knows of\norbs!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Only he knows\nthe orb's gift!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a drunken\nfighter.", 
        "health": "And a bottle\nof...", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Yo ho ho...\nand a bottle...\nof rum...\nhic...", 
        "keyword_1": "STONE", 
        "keyword_2": "RUM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The yellow stone\nis in the\ndungeon\nDespise...", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Rum... hic...", 
        "name": "Joe", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Give me rum?...", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ah, be a Joe!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thanxth...\nmy friend Joe\ncan help with\nthe stones...\nhic...", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a bard in green.", 
        "health": "Shhh", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Shhh, I'm\nplaying!", 
        "keyword_1": "SHHH", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Yes, shhh!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The mantra for\nthe shrine of\ncompassion\nis 'MU'!", 
        "name": "Cricket", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Now wilt thou\nbe quiet?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I am going to\ncall the guards!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thanks.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a cheerful\nguard.", 
        "health": "I am fully\nhealed.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a guard\nof course!", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "COMP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "We guards have\na lot of\ncompassion.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "We always say:\nLet all others'\ntroubles be as\nthine own!", 
        "name": "a guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou kill\nnon-evil\ncreatures?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Good.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "That does not\nshow compassion!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small child.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am learning\ncompassion.", 
        "keyword_1": "LEARN", 
        "keyword_2": "COMP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The solution to\nones problems\noften lies in\nsolving others!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Never care so\nmuch for thyself\nthat thou cannot\ncare for others!", 
        "name": "a child", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Know ye the\nmantra of\ncompassion?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ask Cricket!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tired\nshepherd.", 
        "health": "Good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I watch over\nthe children.", 
        "keyword_1": "CHILD", 
        "keyword_2": "COMP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It takes a\ngood deal of\ncompassion to\ndeal with\nchildren!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Compassion\nstrengthens the\nsoul as\nknowledge\ntempers the\nmind!", 
        "name": "Shalimar", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Have any kids?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou dost know\nwhat I mean!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an injured\nperson.", 
        "health": "Not so well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I know a\nterrible secret!", 
        "keyword_1": "SECRET", 
        "keyword_2": "MOND", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Mondain's\ninfluence has\nnot left the\nworld!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "An artifact\nremains! I heard\nat Buccaneer's\nDen!", 
        "name": "Sebastian", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou find\nand destroy it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then ask at the\npub there of\nthe skull!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a druid.", 
        "health": "All right.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am looking\nfor Julio.", 
        "keyword_1": "JULIO", 
        "keyword_2": "COMP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "He knows the\ntrue nature of\ncompassion.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Seek out Julio\nand ask him of\ncompassion!", 
        "name": "Shapero", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou on the\nQuest of the\nAvatar?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Find the shrine\nof compassion\neast across 2\nbridges!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a solemn bard.", 
        "health": "Solemn.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I seek the\ntrue nature\nof things!", 
        "keyword_1": "NATURE", 
        "keyword_2": "COMP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "All things have\na true nature!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Compassion\nderives itself\nfrom unending\nlove!", 
        "name": "Julio", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou know\nthe true nature\nof all things?", 
        "question_no_answer": "No mortal can.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou art a liar\nand a braggart.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise shepherd.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I escaped\nMagincia!", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGIN", 
        "keyword_2": "PRIDE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Pride was too\ngreat in\nMagincia!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The city was\ndestroyed by\ndaemons for\nits pride!", 
        "name": "Mentor", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou proud?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Pride exists\nwithout truth,\nlove, or\ncourage!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "That is not\na virtue!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a poor beggar.", 
        "health": "I fear I\nshall die of\nstarvation!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I have no job so\nnow I beg!", 
        "keyword_1": "STARV", 
        "keyword_2": "BEG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have not eaten\nin a week!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Please! Help me!", 
        "name": "Sprite", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Wilt thou\nhelp me?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I shall starve\nto death!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "In return I\nshall tell thee\nthat Pepper\nknows of the\nrune!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a 6 foot 5,\ngreat warrior.", 
        "health": "I am good\nand strong!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I lead into\nbattle!", 
        "keyword_1": "WARR", 
        "keyword_2": "BATT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A great warrior\nis a valiant\nwarrior!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I desire to\nfight again in\nbattle!", 
        "name": "Geoffrey", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou\nvaliant!", 
        "question_no_answer": "To flee battle\nshows cowardice!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Perhaps I could\nsomeday join\nthee!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mysterious\nwarrior.", 
        "health": "Outstanding!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I battle for\nLord British!", 
        "keyword_1": "WARR", 
        "keyword_2": "BATT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Thou must battle\nlong and hard\nto be a warrior.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Battles are few\nand too many!", 
        "name": "Lord Robert", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Are you a\nvaliant warrior?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou art a wimp!", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou dost\ndeserve the\nrune, ask\nNostro!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a 5 foot\npregnant woman.", 
        "health": "Fine, all but\nthe lump in\nmy stomach.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I watch over\nmy sheep.", 
        "keyword_1": "PREG", 
        "keyword_2": "SHEEP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It's no fun\nto be pregnant.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I can't stand\nsheep!", 
        "name": "Lady Donna", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Why, art thou\nthe father?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thank god!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Wait till I\ntell my husband!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wounded\nfighter!", 
        "health": "Poor.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I search the\ndungeons!", 
        "keyword_1": "DUNG", 
        "keyword_2": "ROOM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I fell in\nthe dungeon\n'Destard'.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Therein use the\nstones found in\nthe connecting\ndungeons!", 
        "name": "Bengrod", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou found\nits altar room?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Find it!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It connects with\nCovetous, Shame\nand Hythloth!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a noble fighter.", 
        "health": "Very well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I search\nfor valiant\nfighters!", 
        "keyword_1": "EVIL", 
        "keyword_2": "KILL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Kill not\nnon-evil\ncreatures but\nstill always\nstand thy\nground!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Let them flee\ninstead. Never\nflee uninjured!", 
        "name": "Sir William", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou\nvaliant?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I see.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Strive ye to\ndefeat all evil!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mighty\nwarrior!", 
        "health": "Excellent.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I fight for\nvalor!", 
        "keyword_1": "VALOR", 
        "keyword_2": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The valiant soul\nfears not its\nown visage!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The mantra need\nbe known, ask\nAesop!", 
        "name": "Sir Hrothgar", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou the\nmost valiant of\nsouls?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou should seek\nthe shrine of\nvalor!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "This is not\nlikely!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a stern guard.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "We guard the\ngates and these\npassages!", 
        "keyword_1": "GATES", 
        "keyword_2": "PASSAG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The gates\nof Jhelom.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "These passages\nare restricted.", 
        "name": "A guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small man.", 
        "health": "Well enough.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I search\nfor valor!", 
        "keyword_1": "VALOR", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I find that 'tis\neasy to be brave\nfrom a safe\ndistance!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The mantra of\nvalor is 'RA'.\nUse it in the\nshrine on the\nnext isle!", 
        "name": "Aesop", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Know what\nI mean?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou art brave!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thats my\nproblem.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a grave fighter.", 
        "health": "So so.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I search the\ndungeons.", 
        "keyword_1": "DUNG", 
        "keyword_2": "STON", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I seek the\nred stone.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It is found on\nan altar!", 
        "name": "Gravnor", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou\nhave it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "It lies in the\ndungeon Destard!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "No wonder I\ncan't find it!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a beautiful\nmage.", 
        "health": "Well enough.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am locked up\nin this tower.", 
        "keyword_1": "TOWER", 
        "keyword_2": "CRIMES", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I am being\npunished for my\ncrimes.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Does not matter,\nI can help thee!", 
        "name": "Senora", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou have\na ship?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then thou dost\nneed a sextant.\nAsk the barkeep\nfor he knows\nmore!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a withering\nsoul.", 
        "health": "Very near death!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I built these\npassages and\nthey walled\nme in!", 
        "keyword_1": "PASSAG", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "This passage\nruns around the\ncity!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The rune is\nburied in a\ntower!", 
        "name": "Nostro", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou lead\nme out?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou art a cad!\nand I will still\nfollow!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I am saved!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a ranger with a\nfar away look.", 
        "health": "Quite well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek the\ninner light!", 
        "keyword_1": "LIGHT", 
        "keyword_2": "YEW", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I come from\nSkara Brae and\nam on my way to\nYew.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "'Tis a city\nbased in the\nvirtue of\njustice!", 
        "name": "Luke", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou been\nto Skara Brae?", 
        "question_no_answer": "'Tis a spiritual\ncity!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "A fine city!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "the housekeeper.", 
        "health": "Good!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am the\nhousekeeper.", 
        "keyword_1": "HOUSE", 
        "keyword_2": "ROOM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I clean\nthe rooms.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "That's a strange\none at the\nend. People\noften disappear.", 
        "name": "Max", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Is there some\nproblem with thy\nroom?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh, thou had\nme worried!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I am very sorry\nI will correct\nit right away!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a strange\nperson.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I seek the stone", 
        "keyword_1": "STONE", 
        "keyword_2": "RED", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The red stone.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Red is for valor\na virtue of the\navatar!", 
        "name": "X", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou an\navatar?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then thou shalt\nneed the red\nstone in one\naltar room to\nget the third\npart of a key!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Wow!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a valiant\nwarrior.", 
        "health": "Only minor\nwounds!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I fight battles!", 
        "keyword_1": "BATTLE", 
        "keyword_2": "VALOR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "True valor is\nseen not in the\nforce of arms,\nbut in the force\nof will!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I display my\nvalor in battle.", 
        "name": "Slithe", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou\nvaliant?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Coward.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then never flee\nunless the need\nis dire!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a thin fighter.", 
        "health": "Couldn't be\nbetter!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I fight\nwith valor!", 
        "keyword_1": "VALOR", 
        "keyword_2": "BRAVE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "There is no\nholier spot of\nground than\nwhere defeated\nvalor lies.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Be brave for\nthere is much\nto dare!", 
        "name": "Timrod", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou brave?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Coward.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Fortune helps\nthe brave!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a quiet druid.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I strive to\nunderstand\njustice.", 
        "keyword_1": "JUST", 
        "keyword_2": "UNDER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "True justice\nsatisfies all,\nfalse none.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Let justice be\nthy calling not\nthy excuse!", 
        "name": "Jaana", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou just?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Many a grave has\nbeen unjustly\nfilled in the\nname of justice.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall guard.", 
        "health": "Yes.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "To guard\nthe court.", 
        "keyword_1": "JUST", 
        "keyword_2": "COURT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A good life is\ninspired by love\nand guided by\nknowledge.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Within this\nchamber justice\nis served.", 
        "name": "a guard", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou have\nbusiness before\nthe court?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then do not\ndisturb the\nproceedings!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then enter.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a big guard.", 
        "health": "Fit.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "We guard\nthe jail.", 
        "keyword_1": "MISD", 
        "keyword_2": "FELON", 
        "keyword_response_1": "That'll be the\nleft cell.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "That'll be the\nright hand cell.\ncareful in\nthere!", 
        "name": "a guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou come\nto turn thyself\nin?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Just visiting,\neh.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "In which cell\ndost thou\nbelong, felonies\nor misdemeanors.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a solemn druid.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I make spells.", 
        "keyword_1": "SPELLS", 
        "keyword_2": "MANDRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I invented\nquickness!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Mandrake root is\nfound only in\nthe Fens of the\nDead and in the\nBloody Plains\nwhere the ground\nis always damp.", 
        "name": "Calumny", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Can thou\ncast it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Adept.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It requires but\none bloodmoss!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise judge.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I decide\njustice.", 
        "keyword_1": "JUST", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Justice is truth\nin action!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It is\nhidden well!", 
        "name": "Talfourd", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Can thou\nhonestly claim\nto be guilty of\nno crime ever?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then do thy\npenance in a\ncell, and with\nthe felon\nsearch ye well.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Doubtful.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a burning fire.", 
        "health": "Bright.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I hold the\nfabric of the\ntrue nature of\njustice.", 
        "keyword_1": "JUST", 
        "keyword_2": "FABR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The virtue of\njustice draws\nits nature from\nthe principles\nof truth and\nlove!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Of justice.", 
        "name": "Flamis", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Hast thou always\nbeen just?", 
        "question_no_answer": "At least thou\nart honest.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Unlikely.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a chanting\ndruid.", 
        "health": "Beh... Beh...", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Beh... Beh...", 
        "keyword_1": "BEH...", 
        "keyword_2": "BEH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Beh... Beh...", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Beh... Beh...", 
        "name": "Silent", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise druid.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Welcome thee to\nYew, city of\njustice!", 
        "keyword_1": "JUST", 
        "keyword_2": "YEW", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Love no one more\nthan the truth,\nfor justice\nseeks no favors.\nTemper thy\njustice with\nunderstanding.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yes 'tis a\nfair city!", 
        "name": "Dwp", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou\nlike it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A pity.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Let it be\nas thine!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a poor beggar.", 
        "health": "Well treated.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I have sinned.", 
        "keyword_1": "SINNED", 
        "keyword_2": "FELON", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have gotten\nchests in the\ntownes and\nkilled non-evil\ncreatures.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "He is a mean\nnasty ugly\nvillain!", 
        "name": "a poor beggar", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Should thou be\nin with the\nfelon?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Good.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou art in the\nwrong cell.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mean nasty\nugly villain!", 
        "health": "Hungry!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I eat people\nwho bug me!", 
        "keyword_1": "VILL", 
        "keyword_2": "PEOPLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "That's me\nalright!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Like thee!", 
        "name": "Vorpal", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou here\nto bug me?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Well thou art!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Eat death,\nscum puppy!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 60
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a sleek ranger.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I search for\na home.", 
        "keyword_1": "HOME", 
        "keyword_2": "RANGE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "On the range!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Where the deer\nand the antelope\nplay.", 
        "name": "a ranger", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Ever heard of\nsuch a place?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ah, what'ya have\nto ruin it for!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Seldom is heard\na discouraging\nword!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small child.", 
        "health": "I am fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I work for\nJones.", 
        "keyword_1": "JONES", 
        "keyword_2": "QUEST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I think Indi's\non a quest!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I'm not so sure,\nbut it should be\nfun!", 
        "name": "Short Round", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou\nhaving fun?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I am so sorry we\nall wish you\nwould!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Write to Lord\nBritish and tell\nhim!!!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a withered form.", 
        "health": "I am starving\nand sick.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "See my poor baby\nI beg for him.", 
        "keyword_1": "BABY", 
        "keyword_2": "JUST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Oh, no, my baby\nis dying!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Jaana may\njoin thee!", 
        "name": "Frida", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Wilt thou give\nme money so that\nI can get my\nbaby healed?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Evil wretch,\ncurse thee!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou art kind\nand just!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a thin man.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I take council.", 
        "keyword_1": "COUN", 
        "keyword_2": "JUST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "On justice.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Justice is\nhardest to find\nat the point of\na sword, the\nsteel is an\nagent of\njustice,\nhumanity the\nperpetrator!", 
        "name": "Pinrod", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Fight ye for\njustice?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Cad.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good, the\ndruids chant\nthe mantra!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a big guard.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "To preserve\nthe peace and\ninsure justice!", 
        "keyword_1": "PEACE", 
        "keyword_2": "JUST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A good life is\ninspired by love\nand guided by\ntruth!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Justice means\nnot only to\npunish the bad\nbut also to\nreward the good!", 
        "name": "a guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou\nalways just?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Strive to be!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Unlikely!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wandering\ndruid.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek justice.", 
        "keyword_1": "JUST", 
        "keyword_2": "SHRI", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Learn at\nthe shrine!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The shrine is to\nthe east then\nnorth!", 
        "name": "Druid", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou have\nthe rune?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ask Talfourd for\nhe knows of the\nrune.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Now learn the\nmantra, and seek\nthe green stone\nin 'Wrong'!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an agile tinker.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I care for\nthe poor.", 
        "keyword_1": "CARE", 
        "keyword_2": "POOR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Self\npreservation is\nthe first law of\nnature; self\nsacrifice the\nhighest rule\nof grace.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Within this\nhouse are many\npoor and\ndestitute souls.", 
        "name": "Julia", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Wilt thou help?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Bum.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I would\njoin thee.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a seasoned\nblacksmith.", 
        "health": "Quite well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I forge weapons.", 
        "keyword_1": "WEAP", 
        "keyword_2": "MYSTIC", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I make the\nvery best!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Ah, yes, the\nmystic weapons,\nand armour, my\ngreatest work!\nThose I gave\nunto Sir Simon\nand Lady Tessa.", 
        "name": "Zircon", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Seek thee\na weapon?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Hmmm.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ask at the\ncounter!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a sickly\nlittle man.", 
        "health": "I am very sick,\nhelp me!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I have none,\nhelp me.", 
        "keyword_1": "HELP", 
        "keyword_2": "SICK", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I need money\nto cure my\nsickness.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I have terminal\nleg rot.", 
        "name": "Bob the Beggar", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou\nany money?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then join me and\nwe can beg\ntogether!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then please\nshare it\nwith me!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small\nmuddy girl.", 
        "health": "I am hungry.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I'm an\nundernourished\nbeggar girl.", 
        "keyword_1": "HUNG", 
        "keyword_2": "FOOD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have not eaten\nin days.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Oh, thou art\na kind soul!", 
        "name": "Linda Sue", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Could thou spare\na nibble of\nfood?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh, I see.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I would greatly\nappreciate that.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a fading man.", 
        "health": "I am barely\nconscious.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I shall\ndie soon.", 
        "keyword_1": "DIE", 
        "keyword_2": "CONSC", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I suffer from a\ntsetse byte!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I will soon\nsleep forever.", 
        "name": "Gimble", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Could thou spare\na gold piece so\nI may buy a\nlast drink?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I am saddened.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Remember Azure\nknows of the\nrune!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 40
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a ragged soul.", 
        "health": "Ailing.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "To redeem\nmyself!", 
        "keyword_1": "REDEEM", 
        "keyword_2": "SKULL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I will not speak\nof my sin!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I used it!", 
        "name": "Jude", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "If I help thee,\nwilt thou swear\nto only use it\nat the mouth of\nthe Abyss to\ndestroy it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It can be found\nat lat-P'F\"\nlong-M'F\" on the\ndarkest night!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an old\nragged man.", 
        "health": "I am old\nand weak.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a peasant,\nI hear many\nthings.", 
        "keyword_1": "HEAR", 
        "keyword_2": "STONE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "What does thou\nwish to know?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The stone of\nsacrifice is\norange in color\nand used in the\naltar rooms of\nlove and\ncourage!", 
        "name": "Alkerion", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Seeketh thou?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good luck.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a stocky ranger.", 
        "health": "Well enough.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am trying to\nget a room.", 
        "keyword_1": "ROOM", 
        "keyword_2": "SKARA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have travelled\nclear from\nSkara Brae.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The rune of our\ncity is missing!", 
        "name": "Mike Ward", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Know thee\nof the rune?", 
        "question_no_answer": "It is not in\nSkara Brae.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It is the key to\nthe shrine of\nspirituality!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a teenage boy.", 
        "health": "Fine, thanks.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I give out\nflowers. Here\nyou are!", 
        "keyword_1": "FLOWER", 
        "keyword_2": "KIND", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The way I figure\nit, if thou art\nkind to others\nthey will have\nreason to be\nkind in return!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yes, give all\nthat thou can\nunto the needy!", 
        "name": "Alex", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou give?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a rotund tinker.", 
        "health": "OK.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I welcome thee\nunto Minoc, city\nof sacrifice!", 
        "keyword_1": "SACR", 
        "keyword_2": "VIRTUE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Self-sacrifice\nis a needed\nvirtue!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Avatars strive\nto be virtuous.", 
        "name": "Shentis", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou strive\nfor virtue?", 
        "question_no_answer": "An avatar thou\nart not!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then perhaps\nthou shalt\nbecome an\navatar!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a cute bard.", 
        "health": "Very well\nindeed!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I sing songs!", 
        "keyword_1": "SING", 
        "keyword_2": "SONG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I sing songs!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Very well,\nthe raven sings,\nthe raven saw\nand in the corn\nhe sayeth 'CAH'.", 
        "name": "Singsong", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou\nlike it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad...", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thanks.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a meek shepherd.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I stand here\nand think.", 
        "keyword_1": "THINK", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Oh, just\nabout things.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Listen to the\nbard's song for\nin its verse\nlies the key!", 
        "name": "Damon", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Can't a man\njust think\nto himself?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh, yes\nI can thou\nbandersnatch!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Well I hope so!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 10
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a happy tinker.", 
        "health": "O.K. I guess.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "This and that.", 
        "keyword_1": "THIS", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "And that...", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The rune of\nsacrifice is\nhard to get. It\nlies within the\nfires of the\nforge!", 
        "name": "Mischief", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Hast thou\nthe rune?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Return when thou\ndost find it!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then ask\nAlkerion of the\nstone!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tinker at\nthe table.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I carve runes.", 
        "keyword_1": "RUNES", 
        "keyword_2": "SACRI", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I carve runes\nfor passage into\nthe shrines!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Ask my sister,\nMischief.", 
        "name": "Azure", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou\nseek a rune?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I see.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Which?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wandering\ntinker.", 
        "health": "Been better.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek the\nwisdom of the\nshrine of\nsacrifice.", 
        "keyword_1": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "But first I need\nthe mantra!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I am told that a\nhidden shepherd\nknows the\nmantra.", 
        "name": "Merida", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Know ye\nthe mantra?", 
        "question_no_answer": "The shrine is on\na lake to the\neast!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a massive guard.", 
        "health": "Quite.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "To guard\nof course.", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "LIFE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I often wonder\nif I will ever\nhave to give my\nlife in the line\nof duty.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "One life\nfor many!", 
        "name": "a guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Understand\nmy dilemma?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Of course, if it\ncame down to it,\nI hope I would\ndo it!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a handsome\nfighter.", 
        "health": "Very well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am towne\nleader", 
        "keyword_1": "LEAD", 
        "keyword_2": "HONOR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "'Tis an honor!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It gives\nlife meaning!", 
        "name": "Dupre", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou try to\nlive honorably?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Fool!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It is a constant\nquest. Honor is\nlike finely\npolished armour.\nWithout constant\ncare, it will\nsoon tarnish!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mystic wizard.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I create magical\nfields.", 
        "keyword_1": "FIELDS", 
        "keyword_2": "NIGHT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Poison is my\nfavorite.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Nightshade may\nbe found only\nnear lat-J'F\"\nlong-C'O\" only\non the darkest\nof nights!", 
        "name": "Virgil", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Is it thine?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Well I\ndon't care!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Bravo!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a sleepy\nfighter.", 
        "health": "Tired.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I drink a toast\nto honor!", 
        "keyword_1": "HONOR", 
        "keyword_2": "NOTHIN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "What is left\nwhen honor is\nlost?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Right, take\nhonor from me\nand my life is\ndone!", 
        "name": "Publius", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou strive\nto live an\nhonorable life?", 
        "question_no_answer": "No honor,\nno meaning!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Honor gives\ngreatness.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a bony skeleton.", 
        "health": "What do\nyou mean?", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I hail from\ndungeon deep.", 
        "keyword_1": "DUNG", 
        "keyword_2": "STONE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I come from the\ndungeon 'Shame'!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I have seen the\npurple stone\nused in the\naltars of\ntruth and\ncourage!", 
        "name": "Skitle", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Ever been there?", 
        "question_no_answer": "It holds items\nthou shalt need.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an ugly sailor.", 
        "health": "A bit\nwaterlogged.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I sail the\nthe seas of\nBritannia!", 
        "keyword_1": "SEAS", 
        "keyword_2": "SEXT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "My specialty is\nnavigation!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Go to the pub in\nJhelom and ask\nof sextants.", 
        "name": "Sailor Sam", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Is it thy\nspecialty?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou must\nnot own a\nsextant, eh?", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good show mate!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a dignified\npaladin.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I search\nfor honor.", 
        "keyword_1": "HONOR", 
        "keyword_2": "DIGNIT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Dignity\nconsists not\nin possessing\nhonors, but in\ndeserving them.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Honor no one,\nbut honor\nitself!", 
        "name": "Aristotle", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou\nhonorable at all\ntimes?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Strive to be as\nsuch.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "That is\nimpressive.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a cowering\nchild.", 
        "health": "Scared!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I ran from\nthe bull!", 
        "keyword_1": "BULL", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A big one, with\nlong, pointy\nhorns!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It is buried in\nthe southwest\ncorner of towne.", 
        "name": "Terrin", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Is it gone yet?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Save me!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Whew, I thought\nit would get me!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a strong\npaladin.", 
        "health": "Extra good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am\nthe welcomer.", 
        "keyword_1": "WELCOM", 
        "keyword_2": "HONOR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Yes, welcome to\nTrinsic city of\nhonor!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Wisdom on the\nvirtue of honor\nis found\nthroughout this\ntowne.", 
        "name": "Rigmore", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek\nthis wisdom?", 
        "question_no_answer": "This is the\nwrong place!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Enter and find\nthy path.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a scruffy\nmerchant.", 
        "health": "A bit\nragged out.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "A trade\nin rumors.", 
        "keyword_1": "RUMOR", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "About what?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "There is a small\nchild who knew\nnamed... Terrin.", 
        "name": "Winthrop", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou\nknow him?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Find him and ask\nof the rune!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ask him of\nthe rune.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall wizard.", 
        "health": "Fully healed.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I cast spells.", 
        "keyword_1": "SPELLS", 
        "keyword_2": "MANDRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Spells of\ngreat power.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Ask at the\nFolley tavern\nof mandrake.", 
        "name": "Swindrik", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou cast\nspells of great\npower?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Dost thou know\ntheir main\ningredient?", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "What is the\nmost powerful\nreagent?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a searching\npaladin!", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek entry to\nthe shrine of\nhonor!", 
        "keyword_1": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The mantra\nis 'SUMM'.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A man named\nWinthrop knows\nof the rune!", 
        "name": "Kline", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Know ye the two\nrequirements to\nenter and use\nthe shrine?", 
        "question_no_answer": "What dost\nthou think?", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "What are they?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a shining\npaladin.", 
        "health": "Superb.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am warlord\nof Trinsic.", 
        "keyword_1": "WARLOR", 
        "keyword_2": "QUESTS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have solved\nmany quests!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The solving of\nquests brings ye\nhonor!", 
        "name": "Lexington", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Strive ye\nfor honor?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then solve\nquests but\nattack not\nnon-evil\ncreatures, and\nget not\nothers gold!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a soulful\nfighter.", 
        "health": "Tired.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek a place\nto rest.", 
        "keyword_1": "REST", 
        "keyword_2": "QUEST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have quested\nlong and hard.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I seek\nenlightenment\nat the shrine of\nhonor!", 
        "name": "Dergin", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou\nenlightened\nin honor?", 
        "question_no_answer": "The shrine lies\nto the south and\nwest beyond the\nswamps!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a big guard.", 
        "health": "Excellent.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "We guard\nthe gate.", 
        "keyword_1": "GATE", 
        "keyword_2": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Into and out\nof Trinsic.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "'Tis an\nhonorable job!", 
        "name": "a guard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou strive\nto bring honor\nupon the peers?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Dolt.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Dupre, the\nleader of our\ntowne, joins\nmany honorable\nquests!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wandering\nmage.", 
        "health": "Adequate.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek the\nskeleton!", 
        "keyword_1": "SKEL", 
        "keyword_2": "SECRET", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It knows a\ngreat secret.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "About the purple\nstone of honor!", 
        "name": "Quix", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou have\nthe purple\nstone?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Seek it for it\nis very useful!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Use it wisely!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a strong guard.", 
        "health": "Guarded.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "To guard.", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "STRONG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Guarding.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Guard", 
        "name": "a guard", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 40
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a solemn ranger.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek the\ninner light.", 
        "keyword_1": "LIGHT", 
        "keyword_2": "TRUTH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I seek the \"one\ngreat truth\"!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "That which\nlies within\nthe codex!", 
        "name": "Shamino", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek\nthis \"truth\"?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Some things take\nforever but\nbrick by brick\nmountains can be\nbuilt!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an injured man.", 
        "health": "I am grievously\nwounded.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek the\nspiritual path.", 
        "keyword_1": "SPIRIT", 
        "keyword_2": "WOUND", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Spiritual is\nstronger than\nany material\nforce.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Nothing can\nbring thee peace\nbut the triumph\nof principles!", 
        "name": "Emerson", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou good\nin spirit?", 
        "question_no_answer": "An evil path!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "A good path.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall ranger.", 
        "health": "I am alive.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I carry the\nlight within my\nheart.", 
        "keyword_1": "LIGHT", 
        "keyword_2": "PHILOS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The light of\nphilosophy.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "In philosophical\nminds the\nfamiliar excites\nwonder!", 
        "name": "Santayana", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou always\ntread the right\npath?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Few can, but\nstrive to do so!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Doubtful!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a very small\nwizard.", 
        "health": "Superior!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I cast great\nbig spells!", 
        "keyword_1": "SPELLS", 
        "keyword_2": "NIGHT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I can cast:\njinx, kill,\nand view!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yes, ask the\nbarkeep at\n'The Axe-n-Ale'\nin Vesper about\nnightshade.", 
        "name": "Presto", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou know\nwhat these\nspells have in\ncommon?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Guess!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "What?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a hungry beggar.", 
        "health": "I am not\nat all well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I beg for food\nand money.", 
        "keyword_1": "FOOD", 
        "keyword_2": "MONEY", 
        "keyword_response_1": "To eat!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "To buy food!", 
        "name": "Granted", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Wilt thou give\nme food or\nmoney?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Jerk!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "In return I will\ntell thee that\nthe ankh knows\nof the rune and\nmy friend Ambule\nknows the\nmantra!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a radiant\nranger.", 
        "health": "I am fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am reading the\nwizard's\njournal.", 
        "keyword_1": "JOURN", 
        "keyword_2": "STONE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It tells of the\nwhite stone.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It is no longer\nin the dungeon\nHythloth, it\nis gone!", 
        "name": "Mitre", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Wilt thou try to\nrecover it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ask of the stone\nat the Tap in\nTrinsic!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a great\nphilosopher.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I teach.", 
        "keyword_1": "TEACH", 
        "keyword_2": "NOBLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "When one has\npity on all\nliving creatures\nthen is one\nnoble.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "If one speaks or\nacts with pure\nthought,\nhappiness will\nfollow like a\nshadow that\nnever leaves.", 
        "name": "Buddha", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a skilled\nranger.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I strive along\nthe path.", 
        "keyword_1": "PATH", 
        "keyword_2": "JOURN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Success is a\njourney, not a\ndestination.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "May thou always\ndesire more than\nthou can\naccomplish!", 
        "name": "Michaelangelo", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou far\nalong the path?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Fear not thou\nshalt be.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "This is good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a short dumpy\nman with a book.", 
        "health": "I am fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a teacher,\nI enrich young\nminds.", 
        "keyword_1": "TEACH", 
        "keyword_2": "WORD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I teach of\nthe abyss.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Seek Zair the\nWise in Paws for\nmore on the\nword.", 
        "name": "Romasco", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Know ye of\nthe abyss?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Learn!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "A word of\npassage is\nneeded at the\nlast gate!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise mage.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I write magic.", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGIC", 
        "keyword_2": "BELIE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "One lives by\nbelieving in\nsomething.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Great\ndiscoveries are\nmade by those\nwhose feelings\nrun ahead of\ntheir thinking.", 
        "name": "Carlyle", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou\nbelieve in\nmagic?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I see.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Magic missiles\nneed but 1\npart ash!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise bard.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I write stories.", 
        "keyword_1": "STOR", 
        "keyword_2": "SPIRIT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Stories are good\nfor the spirit!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Remember,\nno one is\nuseless in this\nworld who\nlightens the\nburdens of\nothers!", 
        "name": "Dickens", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou good\nin nature?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I see.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Be sure thy net\ngood well\nexceeds thy\nnet evil!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a gallant\nfighter.", 
        "health": "Excellent!", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I quest.", 
        "keyword_1": "QUEST", 
        "keyword_2": "DANGER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Many quests are\nvery dangerous!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I am not afraid\nof tomorrow; I\nhave seen\nyesterday and I\nlove today.", 
        "name": "White", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou\nfearless in all\nthings?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Danger is real!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Boastful fool!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a silver ankh.", 
        "health": "Strong.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I keep the\nsecret of\nthe rune.", 
        "keyword_1": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_2": "OM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Mantra?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Search for\nthe rune of\nspirituality in\nthe treasure\nchamber of\nBritannia!", 
        "name": "the Ankh of\nSpirituality", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Hast thou found\nthe shrine?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Enter the gate\nof full moons!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a grimy beggar.", 
        "health": "So-so.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I beg for but\nfor a single\ngold piece!", 
        "keyword_1": "BEG", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Oh, please...\nOh, please...", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Ask the child\nnamed Barren.", 
        "name": "Ambule", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Wilt thou please\ngive me a\ngold piece?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Stingy, I know\nthou hast many!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Dear kind soul.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small child.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "No job.", 
        "keyword_1": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I know it well,\nit is 'OM'.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "Barren", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a ghostly\nfigure.", 
        "health": "I am many\nyears dead.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I haunt\nthis inn!", 
        "keyword_1": "HAUNT", 
        "keyword_2": "STONE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The quest is\nnot complete!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The white stone\nsits atop the\nSerpent's Spine.\nIt can only be\nreached by one\nwho floats\nwithin the\nclouds.", 
        "name": "Isaac", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou on\nthe quest?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Hope!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a shepherd.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "A survivor.", 
        "keyword_1": "SURV", 
        "keyword_2": "PRIDE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Magincia was\ndestroyed by its\npride.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Pride flourishes\nin the absence\nof truth, love\nand courage.", 
        "name": "Katrina", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Art thou proud?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Humility is the\nvirtue that\nmust overcome\npride!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thy efforts\nare meaningless.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a shadowy ghost.", 
        "health": "Undead in search\nof peace.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I haunt Magincia", 
        "keyword_1": "PEACE", 
        "keyword_2": "SPIRIT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Peace I can\nnever find,\nforever banished\nunto the realm\nof earthbound\nspirits.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Be not proud of\nthy little deeds\nlest ye too fall\nfrom the light!", 
        "name": "Ghostly", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a jabbering\nskeleton.", 
        "health": "Most superb.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a nobleman\nof great birth.", 
        "keyword_1": "NOBLE", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Me and my\nbrother are the\nlast two of the\ngreat Meridid\nfamily.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "Skullface", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Thou hast heard\nof us of course,\nyes?", 
        "question_no_answer": "You must not be\nfrom near these\nparts!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I thought so.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small ghost.", 
        "health": "Feeling a bit\ntranslucent.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "To haunt\nthis shop.", 
        "keyword_1": "HAUNT", 
        "keyword_2": "PRIDE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A lot of\nhaunting goes on\nround here.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Seek ye the\nmantra for\nhumility, ask ye\nHeywood!", 
        "name": "Casperin", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Know thee why?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Pride!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Pride is the\nsurest measure\nof goals never\nattained!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall ghost.", 
        "health": "Been better.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "Oh, I just\nhang around!", 
        "keyword_1": "HANG", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I was hung for\nmy sin of pride!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The mantra for\npride, being\nthe antithesis\nof humility,\nis 'MUL'.", 
        "name": "Faultless", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Art thou proud?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Pride is evil's\nfavorite sin!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "A grave sin!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall ghost.", 
        "health": "As well as can\nbe expected.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "Haunt eternally.", 
        "keyword_1": "HAUNT", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Pride goeth\nbefore, shame\ncometh after!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Faultless knows\nthe mantra of\npride ask him!", 
        "name": "Heywood", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Art thou proud?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A proud soul\nsurely knows not\nits worth!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou shalt\nfind shame!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a skinny\nskeleton.", 
        "health": "A bit on the\nthin side.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I rattle\nmy bones.", 
        "keyword_1": "BONES", 
        "keyword_2": "PRIDE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I did value\nmyself far too\ngreatly, that\npride was my\ndownfall.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A terrible\nthing!", 
        "name": "Slim", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Art thou\nalways humble?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Take no pride in\nhumility, lest\nye destroy it!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Doubtful.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a crumbling\nskeleton.", 
        "health": "A bit bony.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I once held the\nsilver horn.", 
        "keyword_1": "HORN", 
        "keyword_2": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The silver horn\nmust be used to\npass the daemon\nguard of the\nshrine.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Wierdrum has\nbeen to the\nshrine of\nhumility!", 
        "name": "Banter", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Seek ye\nthe horn?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ask Demitry!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a thin skeleton.", 
        "health": "'bout the same\nas yesterday.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I rattle\nmy bones.", 
        "keyword_1": "BONES", 
        "keyword_2": "HORN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Bones, them\nbones, them\ndry bones...", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The queen of\nlove has a lady\nin waiting, she\ncan tell thee\nmore of the\nhorn!", 
        "name": "Demitry", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Art thou dead?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Watch out\nfor Nate!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ah, too bad!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "rattling bones.", 
        "health": "Haunted.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I haunt,\nand I haunt,\nand I haunt!", 
        "keyword_1": "HAUNT", 
        "keyword_2": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A haunting job\ntakes more than\na lifetime, it\ntakes forever!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yes, I have been\nto the shrine,\nit lies on the\nnorth bank in\nthe isle of the\nabyss!", 
        "name": "Wierdrum", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a dumpy ghost.", 
        "health": "Hic...", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I was once\na powerful\nmerchant!", 
        "keyword_1": "MERCH", 
        "keyword_2": "POWER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "My wealth\nwas boundless,\nI held great\npower!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A proud soul\nsurely knows not\nit's worth!", 
        "name": "Boozer", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Dost thou see?", 
        "question_no_answer": "The world goes\non without me.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "The world goes\non without me.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a fat skeleton.", 
        "health": "Couldn't\nbe better.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I run this shop.", 
        "keyword_1": "SHOP", 
        "keyword_2": "SPOIL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Why, the food\nshop of course.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Well, we're\nexpecting more\nany day!", 
        "name": "Bulbous", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Can I interest\nthee in some\nrations?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I sell only the\nvery best.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Hmmm, our stock\nseems to have\nspoiled....", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a weeping\nskeleton.", 
        "health": "Been better.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I regret.", 
        "keyword_1": "REGRET", 
        "keyword_2": "HUMBLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I was proud,\nstrip thyself of\nconceits, only\nthe humble are\npure!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The root from\nwhich all\nvirtues grow!", 
        "name": "Splot", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Dost thou\nseek purity?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Fool!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then ask the\nsnake of the\nrune and stone!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a blue ghost.", 
        "health": "Not well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I now try to\nunderstand\nhumility.", 
        "keyword_1": "HUMI", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The first test\nof a great soul\nis humility!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Ask the snake of\nthe rune, just\nbefore it\nstrikes!", 
        "name": "Ruskin", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek\nto know\nhumility?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A shame.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou shalt need\nthe rune!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mean looking\nviper!", 
        "health": "Bloodthirsty!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I bring death\nto all life in\nMagincia!", 
        "keyword_1": "STON", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Those who seek\nthe black stone\nneed ask at the\npub in Britain!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The sacred rune\nof humility was\nbanished from\nthis city. Ask\nBarren in Paws!", 
        "name": "Nate", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a horrible\nghastly devil!", 
        "health": "Devilish!", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I welcome thee\nto Magincia!\nProud city of\nthe high seas!", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGIN", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Magincia fell\nunto the realm\nof darkness for\nthe foundation\nof their virtue\nwas ill-placed\nin pride!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "Virtuebane", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Art thou proud?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ah.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a very\nbig guard.", 
        "health": "Excellent.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am the chief\nguard in the\nvillage of Paws!", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "TROUB", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Paws is a great\nvillage and we\nkeep it safe!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Pirates come\nfrom an isle to\nthe east!", 
        "name": "Wilmoore", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou\nmean to\ncause trouble?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Good.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then thou had\nbest leave!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tough girl.", 
        "health": "Right good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am the\nstable hand.", 
        "keyword_1": "STABLE", 
        "keyword_2": "SMITH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I saw the way ya\ndealt with ol'\nRed Eye!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The talking\nhorse!", 
        "name": "Francesca", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Ya haven't come\nto steal a horse\nI hope?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then must be\nto see Smith!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Well the master\nain't gonna like\nthat much!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall\nburly man.", 
        "health": "Fine, thanks.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I'm a\nlumberjack, ya.", 
        "keyword_1": "LUMBER", 
        "keyword_2": "AXE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Wit' my axe, I\ncan chop'm down\nquick, ya.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It's a big\naxe, ya.", 
        "name": "Sven", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art ya a\nlumberjack?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Build up those\narms, ya!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good for\nyou, ya.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a man of\nmany years.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I've been near\nthe codex!", 
        "keyword_1": "CODEX", 
        "keyword_2": "WORD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Its secrets\nare boundless!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A three part key\nand a word of\npassage are\nneeded to enter\nthe chamber. Ask\nmy brother\nbeyond Lock Lake\nof the word!", 
        "name": "Zair the Wise", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Seen it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Seek it!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Wow!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a very\nlarge woman.", 
        "health": "Stronger\nevery day!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am the barmaid\nI serve the ale!", 
        "keyword_1": "ALE", 
        "keyword_2": "BREW", 
        "keyword_response_1": "We have the\nfinest brew in\nBritannia!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "We serve only\nFolley on tap!", 
        "name": "Sal", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou\nfavor Folley?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad,\nit's the best!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "A great mug if I\nmay say so!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a young mage!", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek the\nwisdom of magic.", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGIC", 
        "keyword_2": "MASTER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "My master knows\nthe gate travel\nspell!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "My master is\nMentorian.", 
        "name": "Jingles", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou\nknow him?", 
        "question_no_answer": "He lives in a\nhidden village\nin Lock Lake\nreachable only\nby ship, ask of\nthe gate spell!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall muscular\nknight.", 
        "health": "Tired and\nhungry but\nalways faithful.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I serve\nLord British.", 
        "keyword_1": "FAITH", 
        "keyword_2": "QUEST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I quest always\nfor Britannia!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "My quest is to\ndefeat the evils\nof the world.", 
        "name": "Sir Hobie", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "'Tis thy quest\nalso?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A shame it is!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "We are as one.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small druid.", 
        "health": "A bit hungry.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am here to\nbuy food.", 
        "keyword_1": "FOOD", 
        "keyword_2": "RATION", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Yes, I hear they\nhave the best\nrations here.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Rations are used\nin dungeons.", 
        "name": "Damsel", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou travel\nin the depths?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Probably a wimp.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "In the great\ncastle there is\na secret\nentrance!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a meek shepherd.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I just sit here.", 
        "keyword_1": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Around there in\nthe nook of the\nmountains!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "Wheatpin", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou looking\nfor something?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I see.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "What?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a hooded ranger.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I travel\nthe land.", 
        "keyword_1": "LAND", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Britannia.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Search the\nhills in the\nsouth-east\ncorner of town!", 
        "name": "Barren", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou dim?", 
        "question_no_answer": "We shall see.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I thought so.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small girl.", 
        "health": "Good, thanks.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "What's a job?", 
        "keyword_1": "A", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "Pix", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "And thee?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise lord.", 
        "health": "I am fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am the keeper.", 
        "keyword_1": "KEEPER", 
        "keyword_2": "MYSTIC", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Of what I\ncannot say!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Mystics can be\nfound by an\neight parts\navatar!", 
        "name": "Sir Simon", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou\nattained\nenlightenment in\nall eight\nvirtues?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "The mystic\narmour lies in\nthe centre of\nthe oak grove!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise lady.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am the keeper.", 
        "keyword_1": "KEEPER", 
        "keyword_2": "MYSTIC", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I cannot say.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Mystics can be\nfound by an\neight parts\navatar!", 
        "name": "Lady Tessa", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Hast thou\nattained\nenlightenment in\nall eight\nvirtues?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Alas.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "The mystic\nweapons lie in\nthe training\nroom of Serpent\ncastle!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a short jester.", 
        "health": "Jolly good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am here to\nserve thee.", 
        "keyword_1": "SERVE", 
        "keyword_2": "DANCE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Well, I can\ndance and sing!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "And sing,\ntra la la...", 
        "name": "Asemly", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Does that\ninterest thee?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Well then, I\nguess I'm no\nhelp at all\nthen.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a singing bard.", 
        "health": "Quite well\nindeed!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I sing of\nBritannia.", 
        "keyword_1": "BRIT", 
        "keyword_2": "EARTH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Britannia is a\nland so fair,\nto other lands I\nwould not dare!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I hope someday\nthou may return!", 
        "name": "Little Jon", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "I hear that thou\nart from another\nworld?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Just a rumor.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "What is\nit called?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a white\nstallion.", 
        "health": "Good, good.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Oh, not much.", 
        "keyword_1": "A", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "Smith", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mean looking\nguard.", 
        "health": "What's it to\nya scumpuppy!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "We guard the\nbridge slime!", 
        "keyword_1": "BRIDGE", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "This bridge ya\nstupid jerk!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "Roofus", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou a\nwise &##!?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then just\nbuzz off!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou had best\nditch it then!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall,\nmuscular,\nimpressive\nguard.", 
        "health": "Very hungry!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a guard.", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "HUNGER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I guard\nthe city!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Yes, I am\nvery hungry!", 
        "name": "Rankbreath", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou here\nto feed me?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then thou had\nbetter run!!!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I am grateful.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a scruffy\nsailor.", 
        "health": "Salty.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a sailor!", 
        "keyword_1": "SAIL", 
        "keyword_2": "LIFE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Oh, a sailor's\nlife is the life\nfor me,", 
        "keyword_response_2": "As I sail across\nthe bounding\nsea!", 
        "name": "Sailor", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "The rest?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "And never ever\never do I worry\n'bout the\nweather, for the\nweather never\never did a thing\nfor me!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall sailor.", 
        "health": "Good enough, eh!", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I'm a\npirate matey!", 
        "keyword_1": "PIRA", 
        "keyword_2": "RAID", 
        "keyword_response_1": "We raid the\ncoasts of\nBritannia, fun\neh!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Pillage\nand burn!", 
        "name": "Silver John", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou\na pirate?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou had best\nleave this place\n'fore there's\nany trouble!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good matey!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a nimble thief.", 
        "health": "As good as\nI need be!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "What's it\nto thee?", 
        "keyword_1": "THIEF", 
        "keyword_2": "CLEVER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Yea, and\nclever too.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Thou dost ask\ntoo many\nquestions!", 
        "name": "Slysam", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou\na thief?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Just as I\nthought", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Oh, I'd better\nwatch out!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 10
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a solemn ranger.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I travel.", 
        "keyword_1": "TRAVEL", 
        "keyword_2": "SKULL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The lands of\nBritannia.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Be warned that\nif thou dost\never use the\nskull, except to\ndestroy it, all\nthy virtues will\nbe lost!", 
        "name": "Ragnar", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou here\nlooking for\ninformation?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Then buzz off.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "On what?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 10
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a slinky mage.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a sorceress", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGIC", 
        "keyword_2": "SLEEP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "How about the\nsleep spell...\nsleep...\nsleep....", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A sleep spell\nrequires but one\npart silk!\nsleep...\nsleep...\nsleep...", 
        "name": "Seanna", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "My dear friend,\nmay I help you?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ah", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "How about with\nthy magic?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a sneaky thief!", 
        "health": "Very well!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "At thy service!", 
        "keyword_1": "SERV", 
        "keyword_2": "HYTH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "How about\ninformation?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The dungeon\nHythloth can\nonly be reached\nby a secret\nentrance in the\ngreat castle.", 
        "name": "Jeremy James\nScirlock", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek a\nspecial dungeon?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I cannot\nhelp thee.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Which?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mage dressed\nall in black.", 
        "health": "Dark indeed.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I use\nblack magic!", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGIC", 
        "keyword_2": "MIX", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I cast powerful\nmagic missile\nspells.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Try one black\npearl and one\npart sulphurous\nash!", 
        "name": "Starlight", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou should try\nmy mix of\nreagents!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a big fat troll.", 
        "health": "Shove it!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Aw, buzz off!", 
        "keyword_1": "IT", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Thy face!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "Brigant", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Did thou\nhear me?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I said shove it!", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then do it!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 80
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an ugly orc!", 
        "health": "Good'n smelly.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I smuggle black\nmarket items.", 
        "keyword_1": "ITEMS", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Magic keys,\nmagic gems,\nthat sort\nof thing.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "Boris", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Dost thou need\nsuch an item?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ah well,\nmaybe next time.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I just gave the\nguild shop a new\nsupply!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a towering\nwizard.", 
        "health": "Adequate.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I must\nwarn thee!", 
        "keyword_1": "WARN", 
        "keyword_2": "DOOM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "To step into\nthose woods will\nseal thy doom!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "In there lies\nthe dark side,\nenter not!", 
        "name": "Ignap", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Shalt thou\ngo on?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Wise decision!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Evil shall\nconsume thee!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall pirate\nwith a green\nbeard!", 
        "health": "Jolly good mate!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I'm buying\narmour for my\ncrew!", 
        "keyword_1": "ARMOUR", 
        "keyword_2": "NOWHER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I hope to get\nsome magical\nplate!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Oh, I see.", 
        "name": "Green Beard", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Know where to\nbuy mystic\narmour?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Wish I did!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Where?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a plump\nmerchant.", 
        "health": "Great!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I sell wine!", 
        "keyword_1": "WINE", 
        "keyword_2": "VINTAG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have some\ngood vintages.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I own my own\nvineyards, they\nare on an isle\nnortheast of\nhere!", 
        "name": "Marsor", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou\nlike wine?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Don't know\nwhat thou\nart missing!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ah, then join me\nin a glass!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a jolly\nold soul.", 
        "health": "Jolly good,\nthanks.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a tinker\nby trade.", 
        "keyword_1": "TINKER", 
        "keyword_2": "MACHIN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I create\nprojectile\nmachinery.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Primarily\nship cannons!", 
        "name": "Dancek", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou own\na ship!", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou really\nshould get one!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good odds I\nbuilt the\ncannons!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a cowering man.", 
        "health": "O.K. for now.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am hiding.", 
        "keyword_1": "HIDE", 
        "keyword_2": "SOME", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I know something\nothers want!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I... I...", 
        "name": "Sniflet", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou\npromise to use\nit only to aid\nthe powers of\ngood?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh, no.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "The lighter than\nair device that\nwas stolen lies\nnear the dungeon\nHythloth!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall mage.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "We welcome thee\nto Vesper.", 
        "keyword_1": "VESPER", 
        "keyword_2": "WELCOM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Yes, Vesper is a\nfair village.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Welcome,\nunto Vesper!", 
        "name": "Twin Gates", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou come\na long way?", 
        "question_no_answer": "We are honored\nby the visit of\none on the\nquest!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "We are honored\nby the visit of\none on the\nquest!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a hulk.", 
        "health": "Ug, me tough!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Ug, me tough!", 
        "keyword_1": "TOUGH", 
        "keyword_2": "UG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Ug, me tough!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Me tough!", 
        "name": "Guard", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Ug, thee tough?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ug, me tough!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ug, thee tough!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a meek shepherd.", 
        "health": "Well for now.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I can help thee!", 
        "keyword_1": "HELP", 
        "keyword_2": "SKUL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I know of the\nskull of Mondain\nthe wizard!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "To use it for\nany reason is a\nsign of great\nevil, and no\nvirtue!", 
        "name": "Servile", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou\nheard of it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "It is an\nevil artifact!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "It is an\nevil artifact!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a short, rotund\nman with a hat\nand vest.", 
        "health": "I am fine,\nthank thee.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Traveling dan,\nthe tinker man.", 
        "keyword_1": "TINKER", 
        "keyword_2": "TRAVEL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I am here to\nrepair goods at\nthe guild shop.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I know the world\nis round!", 
        "name": "Traveling Dan", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Been to the\nguild shop?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Best prices!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Great selection!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a sturdy\npeasant.", 
        "health": "I'm pooped.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a serf.", 
        "keyword_1": "SERF", 
        "keyword_2": "WORK", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Serfs work hard\nfor little pay!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I work the\nfields for my\nmaster!", 
        "name": "Balthasar", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou have\na master?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou art lucky\nindeed!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I hope he or she\nis a kind one!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small man.", 
        "health": "I am\nfully healed.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek humility.", 
        "keyword_1": "HUMI", 
        "keyword_2": "PRIDE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "When the 3\nprinciples of\nvirtue combine\nin eight ways\npride has no\nvirtue!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "To be proud is\nnot a virtue,\nand so Magincia\nwas destroyed!\nHumility is the\nvirtue that\nremains!", 
        "name": "Plain", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a slender\nshepherdess.", 
        "health": "I am fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I seek the\nshrine.", 
        "keyword_1": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_2": "HUMILI", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The shrine\nof humility!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The shrine lies\non the north\nbank of the isle\nof the abyss and\nis guarded by\nendless hoards\nof daemons!", 
        "name": "Simple", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Know the isle?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Southeast of\nBritannia!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a fair woman.", 
        "health": "I am doing well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I do humble\nworks.", 
        "keyword_1": "WORKS", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I can help thee\nwith the mantra!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Since humility\nis the opposite\nof pride, so is\nits mantra!", 
        "name": "Gem", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Know ye the\nmantra of pride?", 
        "question_no_answer": "When thou dost,\nreverse it!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Then reverse it\nfor humility!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise shepherd.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am but a\nhumble shepherd.", 
        "keyword_1": "SHEP", 
        "keyword_2": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I am on a\npilgrimage unto\nthe shrine of\nhumility!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It is on the\ndark island!", 
        "name": "Joseph", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Did thou know\nthat there is no\nshrine of pride?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Pride is not a\nvirtue of the\navatar!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Very good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a beautiful\nand impressive\nguard.", 
        "health": "I am well\nenough!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I shall warn\nthee against\ntaking this\ngold!", 
        "keyword_1": "GOLD", 
        "keyword_2": "WARN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It is not thine!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "It is not thine!", 
        "name": "Friday", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Dost thou intend\nto take it?", 
        "question_no_answer": "That is good.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "That would not\nreflect well\nupon thy\nvirtues!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a solemn ranger.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I teach of\nthe shrines.", 
        "keyword_1": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "One >must< visit\neach shrine for\n1, 2 & 3 cycles\neach for thy\npaths to be\nclear!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "Randal", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou visit\nthem often?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Make that the\nfirst goal along\nthy path to\navatarhood!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Very good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise man.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I give wise\ncounsel.", 
        "keyword_1": "COUN", 
        "keyword_2": "VIRTUE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Strive ye to\nknow and\ndevelop the\nvirtue within\nthee.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The seer\nHawkwind should\nbe consulted\n>often< for he\ncan see within\nthee!", 
        "name": "Dirgen", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou shalt\nsurely stray\nfrom the path!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a funny jester.", 
        "health": "I've a\nslight tickle!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Thou thinks\nI'm funny!", 
        "keyword_1": "FUNNY", 
        "keyword_2": "NATE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I dare thee to\nask me about\nNate the snake!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Well, it's a\nlong story and\nwe haven't the\ntime.", 
        "name": "Shazbot", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Don't thou?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ah, too bad, I\nthought I was.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Well good, I\ntry to be!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a slender youth.", 
        "health": "I am very\npowerful!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am an\napprentice mage!", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGE", 
        "keyword_2": "CALUMN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I am the\nCalumny's\nfavorite!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "He lives in Yew!", 
        "name": "Flatbush", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou\nbeen to Yew?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Calumny knows\nthe quickness\nspell! Seek\nhim out!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Calumny knows\nthe quickness\nspell!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a bold paladin.", 
        "health": "I am fully\nhealed!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I travel these\nfair lands to\nspread the\nvirtues!", 
        "keyword_1": "VIRTUE", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "To know thy\nprogress on the\npaths of virtue\none >must< visit\nthe Seer\nHawkwind often!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "Corkrin", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou\ndo this?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou must or\nthou may stray!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall\nnimble man.", 
        "health": "I am very well!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a thief, I\nlike to borrow!", 
        "keyword_1": "BORROW", 
        "keyword_2": "HORSES", 
        "keyword_response_1": "My favorite\nthings to borrow\nare horses!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "You can steal\nhorses in the\ntowne Paws!", 
        "name": "Dyka", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou\na thief?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Likely, thou\nart a wimp!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Watch out for\nthe bull in the\ncorral!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small boy.", 
        "health": "I am fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I know how to\nenter the abyss!", 
        "keyword_1": "ABYSS", 
        "keyword_2": "SHIP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The abyss\nmay only\nbe approached\nby ship!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The ship must\nhave a magically\nstrengthened\nhull!", 
        "name": "Allen", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou such\na vessel?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Ask Blissful of\nthe abyss.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ask Blissful of\nthe abyss.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a small druid.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "Welcome to Cove,\nthe hidden city\nof wisdom.", 
        "keyword_1": "WISDOM", 
        "keyword_2": "PEACE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "Herein is found\nmuch wisdom and\npeace.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Find peace in\nour shrine.", 
        "name": "Frontis", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Art thou well?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Visit our\nhealers, I am\nsure they can\nhelp thee!", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Very good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an old hermit.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I am a recluse.", 
        "keyword_1": "RECLU", 
        "keyword_2": "STONE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I have withdrawn\nfrom society.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Only the ghost\nof Isaac who\nhaunts the inn\nat Skara Brae\ncan tell thee.", 
        "name": "Sloven", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Hast thou\nseen him?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Stay at the inn\nuntil he shows\nhimself!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Ask him!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall wizard.", 
        "health": "Well indeed.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I study the\nmagical arts.", 
        "keyword_1": "ARTS", 
        "keyword_2": "GATE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "There is truth\nin magic!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Since thou dost\nbear the ankh I\nshall tell thee.\nA gate spell\nrequires ash,\npearl, and\nmandrake root!", 
        "name": "Mentorian", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou\ndisagree?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Good.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Well then,\nbegone!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a shining ankh!", 
        "health": "Bright.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I resonate\nwith thoughts.", 
        "keyword_1": "CODEX", 
        "keyword_2": "CHAMB", 
        "keyword_response_1": "To enter the\ncodex chamber.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "One must be 8\nparts avatar,\nhave the key of\n3 parts, the\nword of passage\nand know the\npure axiom!", 
        "name": "the ankh", 
        "pronoun": "It", 
        "question": "Dost thou\nseek help?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Oh.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "What are thy\nthoughts?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a strangely\nfamiliar bard.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I play of love.", 
        "keyword_1": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_2": "PROBLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I light a\ncandle to our\nlove, in love\nour problems\ndisappear.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "But all in all\nwe soon discover\nthat one and one\nis all we long\nto hear!", 
        "name": "Paul", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Wilt thou\nlisten?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "About love.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a singer.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I sing of\nthe children.", 
        "keyword_1": "CHILD", 
        "keyword_2": "WORLD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "All round the\nworld, little\nchildren being\nborn to the\nworld.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Got to give them\nall we can 'til\nthe quest is\nwon, then will\nthe work be\ndone!", 
        "name": "Linda", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Wilt thou help?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Hmm.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Teach them\nsongs of joy!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a mystical\nwizard.", 
        "health": "Fine.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I use magic.", 
        "keyword_1": "STONE", 
        "keyword_2": "GATE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The black stone\nis caught in a\nmoon gate!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Stand where the\ngate of both\nmoons dark shall\nappear. Search\nwhen the moons\ngo dark!", 
        "name": "Merlin", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou\nstudy magic?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Too bad.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Best of luck\nwith thy\nstudies!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an old druid.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I teach\nthe relation.", 
        "keyword_1": "RELAT", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "There are\neight possible\ncombinations of\ntruth, love and\ncourage. Each\nof the eight\nvirtues is one\nof those\ncombinations!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "Draconian", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Knew ye this?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Learn the towns\nand castles!", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Very good!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a majestic\nseahorse!", 
        "health": "I am doing well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I know much\nof the codex!", 
        "keyword_1": "CODEX", 
        "keyword_2": "ABYSS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The shrine ankh\nknows how to\nenter the\nchamber of the\ncodex!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Meditate at\nthe shrines\nof honesty,\ncompassion and\nvalor for 3\ncycles to know\nhow to enter!", 
        "name": "Blissful", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise man.", 
        "health": "I am old\nbut strong!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I speak of love.", 
        "keyword_1": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_2": "HEART", 
        "keyword_response_1": "In love,\nall life's\ncontradictions\ndissolve and\ndisappear.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "Carry love\nwithin it!", 
        "name": "Rabindranath\nTagore", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Dost thou seek\nto carry love in\nthy heart?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Thou art a fool.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Thou art a\ngood soul.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "an old druid.", 
        "health": "I am well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I sit and watch\nthe river.", 
        "keyword_1": "RIVER", 
        "keyword_2": "WORD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "It flows\nendlessly.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The kings of the\ncastles which\nrepresent the\nthree principles\nof virtue each\nknow but one\nsyllable of the\nword of passage!", 
        "name": "Brother Zair", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "Agree?", 
        "question_no_answer": "Indeed.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a slender mage.", 
        "health": "Well indeed.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I know of\nthe codex.", 
        "keyword_1": "CODEX", 
        "keyword_2": "COMB", 
        "keyword_response_1": "One must know\nthe combination\nof the three\nprinciples of\nvirtue!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The combination\nof the three\nprinciples of\nvirtue equals\nthe measure of\ntime and space!", 
        "name": "Spellbind", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a tall mage.", 
        "health": "Quite well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I study the\n'one' thing that\nis the secret to\nthe codex!", 
        "keyword_1": "STUDY", 
        "keyword_2": "CODEX", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I study of\nthe codex!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The one pure\naxiom is more\nendless than the\nchanging tides,\nmore eternal\nthan day and\nnight!", 
        "name": "Shaman", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a fair\nsorceress.", 
        "health": "Well enough.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I ponder the key\nto the axiom.", 
        "keyword_1": "KEY", 
        "keyword_2": "AXIOM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "To the axiom.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The 1 pure axiom\nencompasses\nall things.", 
        "name": "Charm", 
        "pronoun": "She", 
        "question": "Know ye what\nthey are?", 
        "question_no_answer": "The truths of\nthe universe,\nthe love of the\nheart, and the\ncourage of the\nsoul!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "Good.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "a wise mage.", 
        "health": "Well.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I teach of\nthe axiom!", 
        "keyword_1": "AXIOM", 
        "keyword_2": "PARTS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "The whole of the\naxiom is greater\nthan all its\nparts!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "The measure of\nunending love,\nthe limitless\ncourage needed\nto face all\nobstacles,the\ntruth which\nencompasses all\nthings!", 
        "name": "Circe", 
        "pronoun": "He", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }
]
